<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UMD Perspectives</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 14:07:47 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 14:07:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 14</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I wrote this really cool thing the other day, let me pull it out. I came up with a good response. It reads, “It feels good to be Richard, he’s a happy guy who likes learning things and seeing the world: was pretty lucky to be in charge of this one”. It’s a bit of a meta perspective, sort of outside of the body, but yeah. I see the world as this big place with different things that can be inspiring in different ways. It’s just like this sort of buffet of getting to try out all sorts of activities and experiences. My perspective is pretty cosmological. I see myself as this tiny little thing on this medium sized rock in this huge boundless space. This sort of mentality calms me down and destresses me. It’s really cool to be like, stealing a quote, “the universe being aware of itself”. I like working really hard, committing to something, that makes me feel really good. I want to change the world, find the best way to impact the most people by doing things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Um, I would be successful if I’ve been able to okay… well there’s a bunch of differnt things. If I could be a mentor in some aspect, there’s some success. This is gonna sound bad, but A, I want to be happy with myself. That’s a really big thing, and it encompasses all of these different aspects, like health, helping people. I want to make something that other people use, lots of other people use. I want to feel like all of the resources that were put into raising me I will have more than paid back, by doing something useful. And, I want… there’s something else, but I forget. I guess, yeah, I want to be able to give lots of money to philanthropy. I want to redistribute wealth. I want to realize a world where no one is suffering or wanting from Mazlow’s Heirarchy of Needs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I guess, it kind of springs off from the last question. But I’d like to help lots of people, create something that lots of people use. I’d like to travel a lot, be an inspiration to other people. I want to go to space, that would be really cool. I want to live for a long time, like a really long time. But I want to prioritize people suffering in the world versus not suffering against something like going to space. I guess more in the short term, either getting a job (I haven’t had a real job), or starting a company with my friends; so whichever one of those seems to be panning out more successfully. I want to have some kids or adopt them, and teach them about the world. I want to find someone to love, and loves me, stuff like that. Yeah, there it is.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/23/000014.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/23/000014.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 13</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;[Gears are working] I’m goint to try to be succinct. There’s a lot of truth to the cliched phrase, “people make their own meaning”, but people generally are pretty similar. They generally respond pretty similarly to circumstances, and if you extrapolate from lots of people’s values you get a set of shared and consistent values. So, we live in a physical universe, presided over by a bunch of physical rules that we are geting closer and closer to finding out, but ultimately the things the matter are things that are defined by humans. Some of those revolve around our curiousity, finding out things. But other values have to do with being with poeple, especially family. Also, accomplishment and helping. I also have my own set of values that probably matter, but not as much.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So, I don’t think that success is some overall life state. I think that we have lots of different goals, and we’re moving towards lots of different goals at the same time, at different speeds. So for me, it’s important for me to have my bases covered: being in a stable place financially, feeling good about the work that I’m doing, feeling like I’m doing a good job in my relationships. But I don’t think that there’s some life state that means success. I generally feel pretty successful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have fun, help people, maybe not in that order. Yeah, I’m particularly interested in making sure that people in the future have better institutions, particularly around education, because it’s a core part of how people form their identity. Other life goals… spend more time in places that are warm, with people that are smart, and who I like. That’s pretty pretty important. I’ll know when I see, I don’t know my life goals yet. It’s a lot of daily direction, looking for local optima, assuming that those lie along the path of global optima.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/23/000013.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/23/000013.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 12</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I don’t know, I guess everything happens for a reason. You have to work for everything you want, you have to create your own opportunities. You can’t complain because someone always has it worse than you. No matter your upbringing, you have the same opportunities, because it’s up to you to create them. I would quote Ghandi, but it would just seem too cliche - “Be the change that you want to see in the world”. So I would just say amen to that. Also, I think you should travel as much as you can in life.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It would be the point where you kind of have a skill that you’ve mastered. It will sort of define who you are. I don’t only want to make bank, I want to be happy. Looking back I want to see that I took the right path. I want to be happy with what I’m doing in my career and actually be making an impact on others. I don’t know… when my name is said I want people to say, “Yea, that guy’s really good at that thing”. I want to be respected while doing what I want to do, and do it well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Definitely be… in a career that I’m satisfied in, so that it doesn’t feel like work, that challenges me. I want to directly impact people positively. I want to be happy in my personal life. I want to be relaxed, kind of, and I want to be healthy. Like, not on drugs, I’m about the healthy life style. I want to have traveled to every continent except Antarctica, just really travel as much as I can. I want to have an interesting life, do new things every day. And also, I want to have a memorable time, so that I can really look back and see a lot of great experiences, expecially in my twenties. That’s all I got for now, let’s go with that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/23/000012.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/23/000012.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 11</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think you should always be doing the right thing, maintaining the integrity of your work. Whatever you’re doing should be helping people. I think you should work until you can’t work anymore. I think you have to be patient and kind with everyone you meet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think I’m always successful. Successful before, now, and in the future. And I think that my state of mind leads me to thinking this way. I’m always doing something that I think is worthwhile, that has an impact, and I’m doing it well. As long as I’m doing that, I feel successful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Goals in life are… to make the world a better, more efficient, more sustainable place through developing creative, impactful tools and generating versatile machines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/20/000011.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/20/000011.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 10</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I wanna say, “treat others how you want to be treated”, but that’s cheesy. I think you should give and expect nothing in return.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would feel successful right after graduating college, because I will have gone through many internships and experienced a real-life world. Basically I would say success is being able to live a stress free, happy life, while providing for yourself. And, having close relationships with people you can depend on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Marry rich and die young haha just kidding. Probably, gradauate from college. Find a stable job that I enjoy doing. Start a fami - travel the world, then start a family. Oh, also those are like my main goals. I’d also like to help those in need and those who have helped me in the past. I want to be someone that people can depend on, and go to when they need advice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/16/000010.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/16/000010.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 9</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think that the thing I value most in life is free will. I think that people should be able to make their own decisions without interference from anybody else. A lot of people ask why I say this (I’m libertarian), but I’m just scared of being controlled. I don’t like the idea of being controlled, and I don’t want the government controlling my decisions. I’d honestly have an anarchy rather than a communist institution. An example is gay marriage. I support the legalization of it, but I personally don’t support it. I wouldn’t personally do it and I wouldn’t advise someone to do it, because it goes against my religious beliefs, but if some other adult wanted to do it, who am I to say no? That’s another thing, it’s sort of like playing God. If people ask me if it’s right, I’ll tell them what I think, but at the end of the day, they’re entitled to their own decisions, and I can’t force them into not doing something, because that is inhibiting their free will. I feel like a good Christian whould not force people to do things that the Bible tells you  to do, but instead, inform them peacefully and thoroughly why you believe it is right biblically. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would say success, maybe on a more worldly level, is financial stability. Not necessarily rich, but living comfortably within my means would be successful. Living a more biblically correct life, closer to what Jesus would do, you know?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think I’ve already covered my goals in what I’ve said in the previous question. I kind of want to get involved in politics, maybe purport my view of free will. You can’t run a political platform on that, but I would promote free will through the values and policies that I come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/16/000009.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/16/000009.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 8</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Life’s an adventure. If you take control of what you want to do with your life, it’ll be such a wonderful experience. If you know what you want and you take the steps to achieve it then you can do great things and live a very satisfactory life. It’s really about having a vision of what you want to be and taking charge to complete yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I already feel successful in a many ways. But, I don’t think I’ll ever truly be satisifed until I have a monkey and a sailboat. People make arbitrary life goals, and once they achieve them, they say, “Oh I’ve been working so hard and now I have this task completed”, but that doesn’t necessarily make you happy. I have a very open-ended view on what I want to be, theres no way I could categorize myself by one definate vision of success. Specifically I want to create a robotics company. That’s big for me. But really, I see that as a career goal, and a life goal too, but I couldn’t just have that and be happy. I wouldn’t feel alive if I didn’t have a sense of adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find happiness. Just lasting happiness, really. I want to create something that people will say “wow, that’s cool”, that’s one of the biggest things. I want to inspire people with technology. I definitely want to be free and never feel nailed down to things because of money, allow myself to travel the world really, have major adventures, meet awesome people, and… a monkey. There are a lot of things that I think would be great to work on, but it depends on what I end up focusing on. For example, changing the education system woudl really improve things for a lot of people. Changing the political climate too, I feel like there needs a much more logical and fast-paced political system, a different political climate. Those are my thoughts on the US. It doesn’t seem like things are being done in a very planned or logical way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/16/000008.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/16/000008.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 7</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think life is, as they say, a marathon. It’s a series of events, and moments, and lesson learned, all ending up to be a great experience and whatever you make of it. I think life is meant to be lived like art, I think you should try your best to bring out as much beauty from the world as you can, see as much as you can, share as much of what you have with the world. I think it’s really just a journey and every day is just something to experience. Throughout your life you find what you’re good at or passionate about so that you can create something that’ll allow you to live forever. There are no rules to life. People expect that they’re supposed to do this or that at a certain age, but everyone has their own path. That needs to be embraced more. I think the most important thing in life is to love people. Love your family, friends, what you’re doing, where you are, what you have already. It’s about being appreciative of what you have and not comparing that to what you want, not putting importance on material things or jobs. It’s really just about appreciating where you are right now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Success to me, like an overall life success, is being able to sit down, relax, and breathe because I’ve done all of what I’ve set out to do - so much so that everything else feels like extra at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My goals include everything from… I just want to design as much as possible. Designing as much as possible, living in different countries, getting paid just do art, whatever art I want to do. I want to buy my mom a ranch house. I want to create a mural with inner city kids. I want to show the world the real value of art, allow them to experience art in ways that they’ve never had before. I’d like to make life as beautiful as possible for as many people as possible. I want to finish building this camera. I want to exercise and eat healthy every single day, find ways to allow healthy eating to people that don’t have as easy access to it. I’d like to get my own farm and grow my own food. I want to teach and to create a beautiful family.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/14/000007.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/14/000007.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 6</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I want to make the world a better place. I think the world is a beautiful place. We just have to learn to support each other, to make it much better than it is today. I think everybody deserves an equal opportunity to be successful. If people are willing to work hard, then I don’t see why others shouldn’t give them that opportunity. What I find today in most of us, is that we are very selfish. We want the best for ourselves. But selfishness doesn’t help in the long run - it might be satisfying in the short run - but in the long run it doesn’t help. If you lose all that you have but you’ve been selfish then you find that there’s no one to help when you’re in need. So why do I say people are selfish today? You find parents who don’t care who their children will grow up to be. They don’t invest. Once the tables turn and the parents grow old, they have no one to fall back on - there is no progress and support in the family. But if the parents are unselfish and willing to support their children as much as possible, and there is progress in the family. Once there is progress in the family, there is progress in the community, and therefore, progress in the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My definition of success is when I’m at a point where I am fully independent and I can support my family. That’s it, there’s no greater success than that. That’s success for me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My goals. First I’d like to graduate college. That’s my priority right now - with good grades. I’d like to first work for a company that will help show me how to adapt to a professional setting as opposed to a school setting, to develop my skills much faster, to transfer my skills from school to the workforce. Then I’d like to become a full time entrepreneur. The problem is, I’m torn in between the two - whether to just start my own business during or right after college, or follow through with an employment. My other other goal is to have a family of my own and to be happy with someone else, my better half. I want to have good networks and make good friends, to travel, to enjoy the world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/14/000006.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/14/000006.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No. 5</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think really positively about life, I try to see the best in people. I see people in terms what they can do, not what they can’t do. I feel like there’s a lot of opportunity. I try to appreciate what I have because I’m fully aware of my situation. I know there a lot of people in the world that don’t have anything close to what I have. You can see this both materially and in other areas, like relationships. I’m a compassionate person, I can understand what people are thinking, so I can understand them better. A lot of things are devastating, but then I know that there’s a lot of joy. Sometimes I see the world in black and white, but other times I see it very vibrantly, like spray paint or graffiti art.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would call myself successful if I influenced people in some way, or something I did had a positive impact. I’m successful if I’m fully self aware. I also want to live for myself and provide for myself. To me success is achieving something I’m proud of, to even the extent of simply getting to class on time, ranging to raising meaningful funds or creating a successful brand.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’d like to understand people from all around the world, and gain perspective on as many cultures as I can. Ultimately I want to be able to understand where people come from and not have prejudice, and in order to do that I have to understand the culture. I want to reach the limit of my creativity and see how far it will take me. I want to be happy. I want to make others happy. I’d also like to stay in love with bæ ;)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/14/000005.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/14/000005.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
